프리티 리틀 라이어스 지난 이야기
NARRATOR:
Previously on Pretty Little Liars...
경찰서에 가서
모든 걸 털어놔야 해
You need to walk in there
and tell them everything,
about Mona being 'A', Shana taking over
모나가 A였고,
그 후엔 샤나가
넘겨받았다는 걸
where Mona left off, all of it.
Are we in agreement?
합의한 거다?
네가 사라진 그 밤부터
시작해야 되겠지
We can begin with the
night that you disappeared.
I didn't disappear.
저는 사라진게 아니였어요
I was kidnapped and held
hostage for 2 years.
납치를 당했고
2년 동안 인질이였죠
Ali goes rogue and we're just expected
알리는 악당두목이 되고
우리는 그녀 이야기의
배경이 되길 바라는 거야?
to back up her story?
내가 샤나를 죽였어, 에밀리
I killed her, Emily, and I don't know
how I'm gonna be able to live with that.
그 사실을 가지고
어떻게 살아가야 할지 모르겠다구
샤나는 몇 달동안
우리를 연습용 타겟으로 이용했었어
Shana had been using us as
target practice for months.
내가 그 문자를 보냈어
I sent that text.
넌 죽은 상태였던걸
바라게 될 거야
And you're gonna wish you stayed dead.
나에게 말한 사실을
네 엄마가 절대 알아선 안 돼
Your mother can never know what you told me.
D부인이 마을을 빠져나간 밤에
Mrs. D wrote that email the night
부인이 메일을 작성했지만
보내진 않았어
that she skipped town,
but she never sent it.
제이슨 오빠, 왜 뉴욕에 있었던 거죠?
Jason, why were you in New York?
내가 앨리슨을 납치했다고 생각하는 거니?
You think I'm the one who kidnapped her?
아아! 오!
Aaaah! Oh!
오지 말아요!
안 돼요, 제이슨 오빠!
Don't! No, Jason!
괜찮니?
ARIA: Are you okay?
우리가 해 줄 일 없어?
HANNA: Can we get you something?
뭐 좀 먹을래?
SPENCER: Something to eat?
물 좀 갖다줄까?
Some water?
그 애를 혼자 둬
JASON: Just leave her alone.
너희들은 가는게 낫겠어
KENNETH: I think you girls should go.
하지만, 딜로렌티스 부인이...
ARIA: But, Mr. DiLaurentis...
그애는 많은 일을 겪었어
KENNETH: She's been through a lot.
- 하지만...
- 맞아
- SPENCER: But...
- JASON: He's right.
우리 모두 여기서
나가있는 게 나아
We should all get out of here.
드레스 입는 거 도와줄까?
Do you want me to help you get dressed?
괜찮아
No.
장례식엔 사람들이 많이 올까?
Do you think there are gonna be
a lot of people at the funeral?
I don't know.
모르겠어
You can go downstairs.
내려가 있어도 돼
시간 맞춰 내려갈게
I'll be there in a minute.
Okay.
그래
KENNETH: I don't want to see any police...
경찰은 보고 싶지 않구나
장례식장에서건
장례의식에서건 말이다
not at the funeral, not at the cemetery.
경찰도 안 되고
언론도 안 돼
No police, no press.
I took care of it.
그렇게 처리했어요
Did you?
그랬니?
Yes, I did.
네
야, 앨리슨은 어때?
Hey, how is she?
She's getting dressed.
드레스를 입고 있어
그러니까 어떻냐구?
Yeah, but how is she?
She's going to her mom's funeral.
엄마의 장례식에 가잖아
어떨 것 같니?
How do you think she is?
자신을 매장하려 했던
엄마를 매장하려는 거잖아
She's going to bury the
woman who tried to bury her.
궁금한 건, 누가 알리의 엄마를
스펜서네 마당에 매장한 거지?
Question is,
who buried Ali's mom in Spencer's backyard?
It wasn't Jason.
그건 제이슨 오빠의 짓이 아니야
어떻게 그리 확신해?
What makes you so sure?
제이슨 오빠의 얼굴을 봤으니까...
그 개가 시체를 발견했을 때 말이야
Because I saw his face when...
the dog found the body.
시체가 묻혀 있는 곳을
그 개가 알고 있었다는 거야?
A dog who knows where the body was buried?
꼭 A라는 말같이 들린다
That sounds exactly like 'A.'
개들은 땅을 판다구, 알겠니?
그건 개들의 행동일 뿐이야
Dogs dig. Okay? That's just what they do.
냄새를 맡고
땅을 파낼 뿐이라구
They just smell something and they dig.
냄새에 관한 부분은
언급하지 말았어야 돼
You didn't have to mention the smelly part.
Aria, 'A' is gone.
아리아, A는 죽었어
You know that.
알고 있잖아
그래, A는 죽었을지 몰라도
Yeah, 'A' might be gone,
but we still have to deal with Mona.
우린 아직 모나를 상대해야 돼
모나는 알리가
납치됐던 게 아니라는 걸 알아
She knows that Ali wasn't kidnapped.
알리의 얼굴에 써져 있지
Got in Ali's face about it.
우리가 걱정해야 할 사람은
모나 만이 아니야
She's not the only one
we have to worry about.
노엘 칸 말이야?
Noel Kahn?
그는 무슨 일이든 해줄
최고의 사람이야
He's going to do whatever
is best for Noel Kahn.
내가 생각하고 있던 사람은
노엘이 아니야
That's not who I was thinking of.
HANNA: That's not the dress we picked out.
우리가 골라준
드레스가 아닌데
That's not hers, but I've seen it somewhere.
앨리슨의 옷은 아닌데
어디선가 본 적은 있는 옷이야
Why are you wearing that dress?
왜 그 드레스를 입은 게냐?
엄마를 느낄 수 있는
그런 옷을 입길 원했어요
I wanted to wear something of
Mom's to feel close to her.
I got it out of her closet.
엄마의 옷장에서 꺼냈죠
- Change it.
- Dad.
- 갈아 입거라
- 아버지
- 왜요?
- 올라가서 다른 옷으로 입어
- Why?
- Go upstairs and put on something else.
우린 지금 늦었어요
We're late now.
I just wanted to wear something of hers.
엄마의 옷을 입길 원했을 뿐이야
왜 그렇게 화를 내시는 거지?
Why is he so angry?
알리, 네 엄마가
입으셨던 드레스야
Ali, your mother wore that dress.
I know.
알아
She wore it to your funeral.
네 장례식 때 입으셨지
We should go.
가야 돼
가자
Come on.
Coincidences happen.
우연의 일치야
Yeah, all the time.
그래, 항상 그렇지
나무에서 자라는
코코넛 열매처럼 말이지
They grow on trees, like coconuts.
Just waiting for you to walk under them.
사람들이 그 아래를
지나가기를 기다리잖아
♪ Got a secret ♪
Pretty Little Liars
S05 X E03 - Surfing the Aftershocks
♪ Can you keep it? ♪
Pretty Little Liars
S05 X E03 - Surfing the Aftershocks
♪ Swear this one you'll save ♪
Pretty Little Liars
S05 X E03 - Surfing the Aftershocks
♪ Better lock it in your pocket ♪
Pretty Little Liars
S05 X E03 - Surfing the Aftershocks
♪ Taking this one to the grave ♪
한글 자막 적과의 동침
♪ If I show you then I know ♪
♪ You won't tell what I said ♪
출처 미드나잇 / DC 인사이드 기미갤
♪ 'Cause two can keep a secret ♪
♪ If one of them is dead ♪
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
The four of you have had
a very stressful week.
너희 넷은 정신적으로 무척 힘든
한 주를 보냈다
우리 모두는
너의들의 안전을 위해서
I want you to know how legitimately relieved
얼마나 합리적으로
너희들을 구제해 주었는지
we all are that you're safe
그리고 너희들이
로즈우드 고등학교 돌아온 것이
and what it means to have you back
in the halls of Rosewood High School.
어떤 의미인지를
알아주었으면 좋겠구나
돌아오게 되서
우린 행복합니다
We're happy to be back.
But I would be disingenuous
하지만 단기간 내에
모든 게 예전과
똑같이 될 거라는 건
to say that things will
be as they were before,
솔직하지 못한 말이다
at least in the short term.
그 점에 대해 감사드립니다
I think we understand that.
부모님들께도 말씀드렸다시피
As I told your parents,
the school will protect you
학교는 언론과
호기심을 가진 사람들로부터
from the press and the curious.
너희들을 보호해줄 것이다
We appreciate that, Mr. Hackett.
우리는 감사드립니다, 교장 선생님
하지만 이러한
비정상적인 상황에서는
But there are limits to what we can do
under these unusual circumstances.
우리가 할 수 있는 일엔
한계가 있다
이 혼란을 최소화하기 위해서
I need to know that you will do your part
너희가 해야 할 부분을
난 알아야 할 필요가 있다
to keep the disruptions to a minimum.
우리가 여기 있는지 조차도 모르실 걸요
(쥐 죽은 듯이 학교 다니겠습니다)
You won't even know that we're here.
세상에, 교장 선생님은
God, Hackett wishes we transferred
우리가 보르네오섬으로
전학가기를 원하신다구
to a high school in Borneo.
Maybe coming back wasn't such a good idea.
학교로 돌아온 게
그닥 좋은 생각이 아니었을지도
우린 적어도 정상적인
상황인 것처럼 행동해야 돼
We have to at least act
like things are normal.
이게 정상적이라고 생각하니?
This is your idea of normal?
When we were in New York,
Ali's mom was killed
우리가 뉴욕에 있을 때
알리의 엄마는 살해당했고
and now we're in one of
Ali's biggest lies ever.
지금 우리는 알리의 이전보다
가장 큰 거짓말의 일부라구
We can't pretend forever.
우리가 언제까지나
속일 순 없어
Somebody's gonna connect all this to Shana.
누군가는 이 일에
샤나가 관련돼 있다는 걸 알게 될 거야
Yeah, probably Jenna.
그래, 아마도 제나겠지
알리가 뉴욕에서의 일에 대해
거짓말한 걸
I'm more worried about the
people who already know
that Ali was lying about New York.
이미 알고 있는 사람이
나는 더 걱정된다구
Noel and Mona?
노엘이랑 모나 말이야?
And Ezra.
그리고 에즈라 선생님
You know, somebody has to go talk to him
있잖아, 누군가가
에즈라 선생님에게 가서
실제로 있었던 일에 대해
and make sure he's gonna keep quiet
침묵을 지키겠다는
확답을 받아야 해
about what really happened.
- Not me.
- Aria.
- 난 싫어
- 아리아
그는 살았고, 안전해
하지만 우린 끝났다구
He's alive, he's safe, but we are over.
You guys can ask me to do anything else,
앞으로 어떻게 할 것인지
너희들이 물어볼 순 있지만
but you can't ask me to do that.
나에게 그런 요청을 할 순 없어
Mr. DiLaurentis kept the cops away
딜로렌티스 씨가
장례식에 앞서
경찰들을 쫓아 보냈지만
그게 끝은 아냐
before the funeral, but that's over.
경찰들이 알리의 납치 이야기의
I mean, it's not gonna take them long
before they start punching
holes in Ali's kidnap story.
허점을 잡아 내는 건
시간문제라는 거지
And when that happens,
그 일이 닥쳤을 때
I mean, we have to have something
우린 경찰에게
왜 앨리슨이 거짓말을 했고
real to give to the police
왜 우리가 앨리슨을 보호했는지
뭔가 사실적인 답을 줘야 해
to explain why Alison lied
and why we backed her up.
사실적이라니?
Real such as?
누가 그날 밤에
앨리슨의 머리를 쳤고
Real as in who hit Alison that night
and who killed Mrs. D.
누가 D부인을 죽였는지 말이야
We're all thinking the same person.
우린 동일인이라고 생각하고 있잖아
Really, did you start reading minds?
정말로 마음까지
읽기 시작한 거니?
스펜서, 그건 제이슨 일거야
Spencer, it has to be Jason.
I told you, guys, I saw his face.
내가 말했잖아
제이슨 오빠의 얼굴을 봤다구
딜로렌티스 부인이 더이상 제이슨을
Hanna found the email where Mrs. DiLaurentis
도울 수 없다고 쓴 메일을
한나가 발견했어
was telling him she couldn't
protect him anymore.
Protect him from what?
무엇으로부터 제이슨 오빠를 보호해?
제이슨이 그 날밤에
앨리슨을 때린 사람이라구
He was the one who hit Alison that night.
우린 그걸 모르잖아
We don't know that.
말이 되잖아
It makes sense.
D부인은 앨리슨을 때린
사람을 봤다구
Mrs. D saw who hit Alison.
그리고 부인이 뭘 했지?
범죄를 은폐했잖아
And what did she do?
She covered up the crime.
누구를 위해서
그랬다고 생각하니?
Who else would you have done that for?
(bell ringing)
우린 교실에 들어가야 돼
We should probably go inside.
쟤는 제이슨의 짓이
아니라고 생각해
She doesn't think that Jason would do this.
제이슨은 스펜서의 이복 오빠잖아
Jason's her half-brother.
스펜서는 뭔가
더 확신이 필요한 거야
She's going to take some more convincing.
Do you want to do a trip
to Philadelphia tonight?
오늘 밤에 필라델피에 갈래?
필라델피아엔 뭐 하러?
What's in Philadelphia?
제이슨이 왜 그 집에 갔는지
알고 싶어
I want to know what's in
that house Jason went to.
I can't tonight.
난 오늘 밤에 안 돼
Why? Are you hanging out with Travis?
왜? 트레비스와 시간을 보낼 거야?
No. I have to be with Ali.
아니. 알리와 함께 있어야 돼
어디에 좀 데려다 줘야 돼
I have to take her somewhere.
어디에?
Where?
장례식장에
The funeral home.
배움의 전당에 돌아온 걸 환영한다
Welcome back to these hallowed halls.
고맙구나
Thanks.
오, 모든 공란이
채워지기 전에
Oh, I wanted to make sure I found you
before all the good spaces were taken.
널 발견하기 원했었어
핏츠 쌤의 병문안 카드야
Mr. Fitz's get-well card.
You know what happened to him in New York.
뉴욕에서 선생님에게
어떤 일이 있었는지 알잖아
Yeah, he was mugged.
그래, 선생님은 강도를 당했지
He was shot, but he's back now.
선생님은 총에 맞았지만
이제 돌아오실 거야
So...
그러니까...
잠깐만
선생님이 돌아온다니?
Wait a second.
What do you mean that he's back?
여기는 아니지, 학교 말고.
로즈우드에 오신다구
Not here, not in school. In Rosewood.
회복 중이셔
Recuperating.
그거 알고 있었니?
You didn't know that part?
No.
아니
카드에 사인하길 원하니?
Don't you want to sign the card?
사람들 이목도 있고 하니까
넌 해야 한다고 생각하는데
I think that you should,
for the sake of appearances.
남들이 어떻게 보는지에 대해
우리 모두는 신경써야 하거든
We all have to be careful how others see us.
니가 이걸 떠들어 댄다고 들었어
I heard you were floating around with this.
Are you going to give it to him?
에즈라 쌤에게
이걸 전해줄 거니?
Maybe with candy?
사탕도 함께 드려야겠지?
뭐, 배에 총을 맞으셨다고 하더라구
Well,
they said that he was shot in the stomach,
so I thought flowers.
그래서 꽃을 드리려구
아, 좋은 선택이네
Ah, good choice.
Sign.
사인했다
What's it going to be like
알리가 로즈우드 고등학교에 돌아올 때
when Ali comes back to Rosewood High?
어떤 일이 생길 것 같니?
Oh, come on.
오, 제발
If she's still Ali, she wants to come back,
걔가 여전히 알리라면
멈췄던 곳을 택해서
pick up where she left off.
돌아오길 원할 거야
And look at that story she's got to tell.
그리고 걔가 말한
이야기를 봐라
All that drama and danger and suspense.
모두 극적이고, 위험하고,
서스펜스하잖아
Couldn't be more exciting if
she made up the whole thing.
걔가 모든 이야기를 지어낸 거라면
더 이상 흥미로울 수 없는 걸
Hey, Mona, have you seen Noel Kahn?
모나, 노엘 칸 본 적 있니?
Oh, I'm sure he's around
somewhere getting into mischief.
오, 그는 분명 어디선가
못된 짓을 하고 있을 거야
에즈라가 로즈우드로
돌아올 거라고 말했어
She said that Ezra's back in Rosewood.
미안
Sorry.
널 따라다닌 건 아냐
그저 네가 떨어 뜨린 걸 본 거지
I wasn't following you.
I just saw you dropped that.
고마워
Thank you.
I'm really sorry about
what happened to Alison.
앨리슨에게 있었던 일은
진심으로 유감이야
Are you sorry about anything else?
다른 일에 대해선
유감인 게 없니?
하루 동안에 감당할 수 있는
모든 사람들의 주목을 받았어
I've had all the being-stared-at
I can handle for one day.
I'll take care of it.
내가 처리할 수 있어
I know her.
She's on the team, she just transferred in.
내가 아는 애야
우리 수영팀에 있어. 막 전학 왔거든
It's not important. Forget it.
중요한 일은 아냐
잊어버려
에밀리가 돌아오니까 좋지 않아?
Nice having Emily back, isn't it?
핏츠 쌤을 위한 카드에
서명하지 않았구나
You haven't signed the card for Mr. Fitz.
나한테 볼 일 있니?
Can I help you with something?
뭐라구?
Sorry?
사람들은 하루종일
나와 내 친구들을 주시하고 있어
People have been staring at
me and my friends all day.
그래 유심히 살펴보라구
So why don't you take a really good look,
우리 모두는 우리의 삶을
잘 살아갈 거니까, 알겠어?
and we can all move on with our lives, okay?
그래, 죽은 소녀가
더 이상 죽은 게 아니라는 걸 알아
And, yes,
I know the dead girl who isn't dead anymore.
Okay?
알겠니?
난 그저 네 트로피를 보고 있었어
I was just looking at your trophies.
나의 뭐라구?
My what?
보관함에 있는 트로피 말이야
The trophies in the case.
너는 에밀리 필드잖아
You're Emily Fields,
모든 트로피에
네 이름이 적혀 있거든
your name is on all the trophies.
페이지와 이야기할 때
네가 누군지 알았어
I figured out who you were when
I saw you talking to Paige.
난 페이지와 같은 팀에 있거든
I'm on the team with her.
난 시드니 드리스콜이야
I'm Sydney Driscoll.
Sorry for shouting.
소리쳐서 미안해
I thought you'd be taller.
네가 키가 큰 줄 알았어
뭐라구?
What?
내 말은, 넌 키가 크지만,
난 네가 더 클거라 생각했었어
I mean, you're tall,
but I thought you'd be taller.
All the trophies.
모든 트로피를 휩쓸었잖아
I figured you had an advantage.
네게 이점이 있었을 거라 생각했었어
Being tall helps,
키가 도움을 주겠지만
but not as much as everybody thinks.
사람들이 생각하는 만큼
도움을 주는 건 아니야
네가 어깨를 다쳤다고들 하더라
They said you hurt your shoulder.
That's why you're not on the team anymore.
그래서 네가 더 이상 팀에 없는 거라구
잊어버려
You must miss it.
I do.
그럴게
있잖아, 난 3주 전에 전학왔는데
Listen, I transferred 3 weeks ago,
I'm bottom of the roster
선수들 중에 꼴찌야
and I can use all the help I can get.
그래서 얻을 수 있는
모든 도움을 받을 수 있어
What does that have to do with me?
나와 무얼 하고 싶은 건데?
Watch me in the pool.
수영장에서 날 좀 봐줘
15분간 보고 나서
네가 생각하는 걸 말해줘
Fifteen minutes,
and then tell me what you think.
Please?
제발?
(bell ringing)
그들이 널 볼 수 있게 하지마
Don't let them catch you looking.
What do you think?
Somebody's gonna throw a rock?
무슨 생각이야?
누군가 돌이라도 던질까봐?
It's a possibility.
그것도 가능하지
They hate us enough.
그들은 우리를
충분히 싫어하니까
*하트필드와 맥코이 같지는 않거든
1800년대 유혈분쟁까지 일으키던 미국의 원수집안
We're not exactly the
Hatfields and the McCoys.
Nothing so rustic.
그렇게 단순하진 않아
*보르지아와 메디치스와의 관계에 더 가깝지
중세 유럽의 라이벌 가문
More like the Borgias and the Medicis.
그것 역시도
꽤 끔찍하게 결말이 났지
That ended pretty nasty as well, too.
모친 살해가 많았지
A lot of matricide.
You think that Jason killed his mother.
제이슨 오빠가
자기 엄마를 죽였다고 생각하는구나
People are capable of all sorts of things
사람들은 그런 스트레스 하에서는
under the right pressures.
무슨 짓이든 할 수 있지
여기 이 집에도
그런 스트레스가 많지요
Well, there's plenty of pressure
right here in this house.
Why did you send Toby after me?
왜 토비를 내게 보낸 거니?
I didn't.
내가 시킨 게 아냐
He went on his own.
토비가 스스로 간 거야
Why did you lie about seeing
him in London when you hadn't?
왜 런던에서 토비를 봤다고
거짓말을 한 거야?
On a practical level,
there's no difference between me
실질적으로 봤을 때,
내가 거기서 토비를 본 것과
토비가 거기 있다는 것을 아는 것과는
별반 차이가 없는 거야
seeing him and knowing he was there.
Then on a practical level, why lie about it?
그렇다면 실질적으로 봤을 때,
왜 그것에 대해 거짓말을 한 거지?
I was trying to keep Wren out of it.
렌을 거기에 두려고 했던 거야
Mom and Dad are worried enough without me
내가 렌을 거기에 두는 걸
dragging him back into things.
엄마와 아빠는
걱정하실 테니까
And who do you think they're
more worried about, me or you?
그러면 엄마와 아빠는
누구를 걱정하는 거지? 나야, 언니야?
나에 대해선 약간만 걱정하시지만
스펜서, 너를 훨씬 걱정하시지
Worry less about me, Spencer,
and more about yourself.
You brought Alison back home,
safe and sound.
너는 앨리슨을
무사히 집으로 데려왔어
너에겐 잘 된 일이겠지
Good for you.
Frankly, I wish you would have left her
솔직히, 난 네가
앨리슨을 발견한 곳에
where you found her, but you didn't.
그 애를 두고 오길 원했지만
넌 그러지 않았어
She's back in the bosom of
what's left of her family.
그 애는 자기가 떠났던
단란한 가정으로 돌아왔어
Now stay away from her and the rest of them.
이제 그애와
그 가족들에게서 물러나
I'm related to parts of that family.
난 그 가족들과 관련이 있어
언니도 마찬가지고
And so are you.
피는 물보다 진하다구?
And blood is thicker than water?
그렇게들 말하지
That's what they say.
It can also be very slippery.
그건 또한 다루기 힘들기도 하지
우리 집에 그 빌어먹을 방명록을
갖다 줬어야 했다구
He could have just dropped the
damn visitation book at my house.
너를 만나보고 싶었다고 하더라
He said he wanted to meet you.
Everybody wants to meet me.
모두들 날 만나고 싶어하지
제길, 난 여기가 싫어
God, I hate these places.
누구도 여길 좋아하지 않아
Nobody likes them.
난 여기가 질색이라구
Well, I hate them.
My mom always wanted me
우리 엄마는 내가
생명의 본성은 연약하다는 걸
이해하길 원하셨고
to understand the fragile nature of life
so she dragged me to all of my relatives'
funerals
그래서 내가 7살 이후로
친척들의 모든 장례식에
날 끌고 다니셨어
starting from the time I was seven.
All these people I didn't
know standing around crying,
모든 사람들이 서서 우는 이유를
난 알지 못한 채로
꽃냄새에 질식할 지경이었지
me choking on the smell of flowers.
세상에
God.
I'll be right back.
금방 돌아올게
Do you want me to come with you?
내가 같이 가줄까?
No.
괜찮아
기다리게 해서 미안하구나
I'm sorry you had to wait.
Oh, it's fine. It was only a minute.
오, 괜찮아요
잠깐이었는 걸요
감사합니다
Thank you.
내가 어제서야
마을에 돌아왔단다
I only got back to town yesterday.
I spoke with your father on the phone.
네 아버지와 전화통화를 했다
You did?
그러셨어요?
난 가능한한
많은 식구들과 만나고 싶거든
I like to meet as many
family members as I can.
That's why I wanted to
give you that in person.
그게 네게 직접
이걸 주려던 이유란다
If I could have returned
for your mother's services,
너희 엄마 장례식 때
이걸 돌려주려 했다면
I would have.
그렇게 할 수도 있었겠지만 말이다
My mother? I...
저희 엄마요? 저는...
I'm sorry, that's Alison DiLaurentis.
죄송한데, 저쪽이
앨리슨 딜로렌티스예요
도나휴 씨 되세요?
Are you Mr. Donahue?
그래
Yes.
I apologize.
사과하마
도프 씨가 앨리슨 딜로렌티스가
여기에 올 거라고 말해줬고
Mr. Thorpe told me that
Alison DiLaurentis was here
and from the description I
had I just assumed that...
설명해준 외모 때문에
내가 생각하기엔...
오, 음, 얘는
내 친구 한나예요
Oh, um, this is my friend Hanna.
우리를 구별하기가
쉽진 않죠?
It used to be a little easier
to tell us apart, wasn't it?
슬프고, 슬프고, 슬프도다
MONA: Sad, sad, sad.
How are you, Hanna?
어떻니, 한나?
I'm okay.
난 괜찮아
두 달째네
Two months.
That's not good.
좋지 않아
실종기간이 길어질 수록
They say the longer
someone's missing the less
돌아올 가능성이 적어진다더라
likely they'll ever come back.
안경은 어쨌어?
Where are your glasses?
더이상 안경을 쓰지 않아
I don't wear them anymore.
You look different.
너 달라 보인다
Look how pretty she is.
얼마나 이쁜지 봐
네가 이 전단지의 사진과
Ever wonder what you'd look like
on one of those flyers?
닮았다고 생각해 본 적 없니?
Probably just put a blank
space instead of a picture.
사진 대신에
빈 공간으로 남겨놔야 했을지도
If Alison's really gone,
앨리슨이 정말로 죽었다면
누군가가 걔를 대신해야 할 거야
someone has to take her place.
What do you mean, "If she's really gone"?
앨리슨이 정말로 죽었다면이
무슨 의미야?
비밀을 알고 싶니?
Do you want to know the secret?
What secret?
어떤 비밀?
The secret to becoming unforgettable.
잊을 수 없게 되는 비밀이지
Hanna?
한나?
Let's go.
가자
언제까지 우리가
마당에 못 나가게 한대요?
How long are they going to
keep us out of the backyard?
경찰은 아직 유효한
범죄현장으로 보더구나
The police still consider
it an active crime scene.
What's gonna happen when
the tape comes down?
저 테이프를 내려 버리면
어떻게 되죠?
집을 팔아버리면 어떻겠니?
How would you feel about selling the house?
모르겠어요
I don't know.
생각해 보렴
Think about it.
저기요, 집을 팔 때
You know, when you sell a house,
don't you have to inform
the buyer of things like
사려는 사람에게
알려야 하지 않나요?
mold and termites and dead bodies?
곰팡이와 흰개미가 있고
사체가 있었다는 사실 같은 걸요
음, 우리가 요구하는 가격에서
Well, we might have to knock
a few thousand off the asking price.
몇 천은 깎아줘야 할 게다
Yeah. Life is full of sacrifices.
그렇죠
삶은 희생으로 가득한 거니까요
우리가 남던 떠나던
저 가족과는 끝내야 한다
Stay or go, we're finished with that family.
You know, Dad, we can sell the house,
있잖아요, 아빠,
우린 집을 팔 수 있어요
we can move away,
떠나버릴 수도 있죠
but we will always be
connected to that family.
하지만 우린 언제나
저 가족과 연결돼 있을 거예요
And you know why.
왜 그런지 아시잖아요
Sometimes complicated problems
have simple solutions, Spencer.
때때로 복잡한 문제엔
단순한 해결책이 있는 법이다, 스펜서
Melissa thinks that Jason killed his mother.
언니는 제이슨 오빠가
자신의 엄마를 죽였다고 생각해요
That's for the police to determine.
그건 경찰이 해결할 문제다
제이슨 오빠의 입장에선
언니가 지적할 일이 아니죠
Well, it's not her job to
point them in his direction.
- What do you want me to do?
- Stop her.
- 내가 뭘 하길 원하니?
- 언니를 말리세요
스펜서, 우리 집보다
더 안전한 곳은 없다는 걸
Spencer, anything that gets the police
to look anywhere other than
this house is a good thing.
경찰은 알게 될 거다
우리 모두를 위해서지
For all of us.
있잖아요, 아빠,
집 팔 생각은 잊으세요
You know, Dad,
forget about selling the house.
우리는 마당에
비단잉어 연못을 둘 수 있어요
We can just put a koi pond out back.
Somebody already dug a hole.
누군가 구덩이는
이미 파놨으니까요
So I have my own healthcare professional,
전문 건강관리사를 두고 있어
Mrs. Esther Walling.
에스더 월링 부인이라는
She comes over every day.
그녀가 매일 들러
It's very nice.
꽤 괜찮아
She says that I'm her
favorite gunshot victim.
내가 그녀의
좋은 총상 피해자라고 말하더군
Look, I know I promised
여기에 다시
돌아오지 않겠다고
내가 약속한 건 알아
that I wouldn't come back here.
하지만 나는 정말로
갈 곳이 없었어
But I don't really have anywhere else to go.
How do you feel?
기분은 어때요?
How do I feel?
기분이 어떠냐구?
I feel like a turkey that's been carved up
온몸이 각각으로 썰어진
칠면조 같아
and then sewn back together.
그리고 나서 다시 맞추어
꿰매 놓은 것 같지
Nothing really feels like
it's in the right place.
제대로 붙어 있는 곳이
않는 것 같아
My counselor says that's...
건강 관리사가 말하길, 그건...
post-surgical mind-body dysphoria.
수술후 정신적-육체적인 불쾌감이라더군
It's supposed to go away, though.
하지만 없어질 거래
Do you know everything
that's happened with Alison?
앨리슨에 관한 모든건
알고 있어요?
Only what I've seen on the TV.
그냥 TV에서만 봤지
She told the police that she was kidnapped
납치를 당했었고
너희들이 필라델피아에서
발견했다고 말했더군
and that you found her in Philadelphia.
Is that the story you all agreed upon?
그거 너희들 모두 동의한 이야기니?
Well, it's the story that she told, so...
뭐, 걔가 말한 이야기니까요, 그래서...
And we have to live with it?
그래서 우린
그렇게 알고 살아야 된다?
That's the deal?
그럼 된 거니?
Yeah. At least for now.
네. 지금으로서는요
Do you know about Mrs. DiLaurentis?
딜로렌티스 부인에 대해서는 아세요?
I know she was murdered.
살해당한 건 알지
And I thought Shana did it,
샤나가 했다고 생각했지만
but the timing doesn't really work out.
타이밍이 정말 맞지 않거든
I had everything backwards.
난 모든 걸 알고 있었어
But once I knew that Shana was following you
샤나가 너희를 쫓는 걸 알았고
and then I saw her in New York
뉴욕에서 그애를 봤을 때
dressed like that, well,
I knew she was 'A' then.
그런 옷을 입고 있길래
샤나가 A인 걸 알았거든
Have you heard from her at
all since you've been back?
너희들이 돌아간 후로
샤나에 대해 들은 것이 있니?
No.
아니요
You have to be careful then,
그렇다면 조심해야 한다
because she's clearly still out there.
샤나는 분명히
어딘가에 있을테니까
Yeah, well, there's cops at Rosewood High
네, 로즈우드 고등학교에
경찰들이 있어요
and all over town,
마을 곳곳에두요
in case Ali's kidnapper comes back.
알리의 납치범이
다시 나타날 경우를 대비해서요
You need to be careful.
조심해야 한다
All of you.
너희들 모두 말이야
I better go.
가야겠어요
Oh, that's a new lock.
오, 새로운 자물쇠야
Let me get that for you.
내가 열어줄게
Um...
음...
thanks for coming and
for letting me see you.
와줘서 그리고
널 볼 수 있게 해줘서 고마워
Yeah, I wanted to see you.
네, 저도 당신을
보기를 원했어요
I watched your videos.
네 영상을 봤어
I'm trying to match your stroke rate.
너의 수영 타법을
따라하고 있어
My stroke rate won't work for you.
나의 수영 타법은
네겐 맞지 않아
Because you're taller than me?
네가 나보다 크기 때문이니?
No, it's not the height, it's your ratio.
아니, 그건 신장이 아니라
비율의 문제야
무엇에 관한?
Of what to what?
Well, what's your Ape Index?
음, 네 에이프 인덱스가 어떻게 되니?
My what?
나의 뭐라구?
Stand up against the locker,
라커에 등을 대고 서봐
touch the floor with your middle finger.
가운데 손가락으로
바닥을 터치해봐
Okay, now reach up with your other hand
좋아, 이제 반대편 손을 뻗어봐
and stretch out as far as you can.
할 수 있는한 쫙 펴서
Now stand up with your
back against the locker.
이제 라커에 등을 대고 서
3인치 정도 차이네
It's about 3 inches.
Your Ape Index is negative three.
너의 에이프 인덱스는
3인치 마이너스인 거야
Should I be taking something for that?
그렇다면 내가
뭘 해야 되는 거지?
No, no, it just means that your reach
아니, 아니,
그건 네 팔길이가
is 3 inches less than your height.
신장보다 3인치가
짧다는 거야
So?
그래서?
So if you don't have long arms,
그건, 네 팔이 길지 않다면
팔이 긴 수영선수를
따라해선 안 된다는 거지
don't copy swimmers who do.
Emily has great arms.
에밀리는 굉장한 팔을 가졌거든
For swimming.
수영하는 데 있어서 말이야
Just adjust your stroke rate.
너의 수영타법을
조절하는 거야
Did you two spend a lot of time together?
너희 둘은 함께
많은 시간을 보냈니?
Training?
훈련하느라고?
Not really.
꼭 그렇진 않아
Not one-on-one.
맨투맨으론 아니었지
But we were together.
하지만 우린 함께였지
In the pool.
수영장에서
And out.
그리고 밖에서
In and out.
안팎에서
Of the pool.
수영장의
Right.
그렇구나
Well, I'm gonna change now.
난 이제 갈아입어야 겠다
Okay.
그래
Abracadabra.
아브라카타브라
Now we have to do something about this,
이제 우리는
뭔가를 해야 돼
because you need a new wardrobe to go
너의 새로운 실루엣에 맞는
with your new silhouette.
새 옷장이 필요하니까 말이야
Hanna?
한나?
That was Ali's.
그건 알리의 거였어
She left it here after
a sleepover one night.
언젠가 밤샘 파티 때
알리가 여기에 둔 거야
Try it on.
입어봐
It's not gonna fit.
맞지 않을 거야
Try it.
입어봐
It fits.
맞잖아
Like it was made for you.
널 위해 만들어진 옷 같다
See? Everything's better with a friend.
보여? 친구와 함께라면
다 좋은 거라구
So what did he say?
그래서 에즈라가 뭐래?
He heard about the story
of you being kidnapped.
네가 납치됐다는
이야기를 들었대
And?
그리고는?
And he said he's not gonna
say anything different
그리고는 누가 묻는다면
다르게 말하지 않겠다고 말했어
if anyone asks.
Good. That's one less problem.
잘 됐네
하나의 문제는 해결됐어
Does he know... about Shana?
그가 아니...샤나에 관해서는?
No.
아니
It's better that he doesn't.
그가 모르는 게 더 나아
Look, Mona thinks that you're coming back
모나는 네가
로즈우드 고등학교로
to Rosewood High.
돌아올 거라 생각해
Does she?
걔가 그러디?
Yeah.
응
네가 돌아온다면
모나는 정말로 어떤 문제들을 만들 거야
She could really create
some trouble if you did.
Mona and Ezra know that
you weren't kidnapped, Ali.
모나와 에즈라는
네가 납치된 게 아니라는 걸 알잖아, 알리
But Ezra doesn't look at
the world the way Mona does.
하지만 에즈라는 모나와 같은 방식으로
세상을 바라보진 않아
Ezra's not a bad guy, Aria.
에즈라는 나쁜 남자가 아니야, 아리아
He's just too romantic for his own good.
단지 자신의 선함 보다
너무 로맨틱할 뿐이지
That's probably why you fell for him.
아마도 그래서
네가 그에게 빠졌을 거야
Okay, I really don't need you analyzing
됐다, 지금 니가
내 성격을 분석하는 건
my personality right now.
정말 원하지 않거든
Here.
여기 있어
네가 부탁한 거야
This is what you asked for.
Keep it. Burn it. I don't care.
간직하던지, 태워버리던지
상관하지 않을게
Do you need anything else?
다른 필요한 건 없어?
Shana tried to kill Ezra,
샤나는 에즈라를 죽이려 했고
and she would have killed all of us
네가 걔를 멈추지 않았다면
if you didn't stop her.
우리 모두를
죽이려 했을 거야
Do you need anything else?
더 필요한 거 없어?
No.
없어
어이, 너희들 아직도
임대할 걸 찾고 있어?
Hey, you girls looking for a sub-let still?
지난 번에 여기 왔을 때
우린 솔직하지 못했어요
We weren't really honest
with you the last time
we were here.
정말 그랬지
No kidding.
훌륭한 감시인이시더군요, 어니
You make a good watchdog, Arnie.
길 아래에서
피자집을 운영하는
I was talking to your friend
who owns the pizza shop down the street.
당신의 친구와 얘기했어요
그가 말하길 당신은 정기적인 고객이며
팁을 잘 주신다면서요
He says that you're a regular
customer and a good tipper.
일주일에 두어번
파이 세장을 사신다구요
Three pies, two, three times a week.
저기에서 군대라도
먹이시는 건가요?
You feeding an army in there?
어떤 군대가
곁들여 나오는 맥주 없이
What kind of army orders all that pizza
and no beer to go with it?
피자로만 주문하겠어?
원하는 게 뭐야?
What do you want?
We're looking for a friend.
우린 친구를 찾고 있어요
이름은 제이슨이예요
His name is Jason.
내가 갚아야 할 것이 있거든요
I need to make amends for something.
그의 옛 술친구인 거야?
Are you an old drinking buddy of his?
여기가 어딘지 알아?
Is that what this is?
그가 *클라크 센터에 있었다고 했을 때
재활원 : 시즌 4 - 23에피 참조
This is where Jason came to get sober
when he said he was at Clarke.
여기에 술을 끊으러 왔던 거죠
그가 언제 왔었죠?
When was he here?
우리 아버지는 여기 안 계셔
My dad's not here.
오빠를 만나고 싶었어요
You're the one that I wanted to see.
어디 가요?
Are you leaving?
장례식은 끝났어
Funeral's over.
어머니는 돌아가셨고
아버지는 나를 필요로 하지 않으시지
Mother's gone, Dad doesn't need me.
나를 원하는 사람이 있다면
그들이 날 찾겠지
If anybody wants me, they'll find me.
오빠의 엄마에게
무슨 일이 있었는지...
Look, what happened to your mother...
우리 어머니는
비밀이 많으셨지
My mother had a lot of secrets.
너무 많으셨어
Too many.
그게 어머니를 죽인 거야
That's what really killed her.
그러면 앨리슨은요?
And Alison?
앨리슨이라
Alison.
내가 이 방에 들어와서
피아노에 앉아있는 걔를 보거나
I come into this room and see her sitting
at the piano or catch a glimpse of her
위층 구석에 잠깐 들러서
going around a corner upstairs,
and I think to myself
걔를 얼핏 보면서
이건 귀신 나오는 집에
살고 있다는 생각을 했었지
this is what it's like to
live in a haunted house.
그러기는 정말 싫다고 결심했었지
I decided I didn't like it.
이걸 보셔야 해요
I think you need to look at this.
오빠의 엄마가 죽던 밤에
이걸 썼었어요
Your mother wrote this
the night that she died.
내가 이걸 어떻게 얻었는지는
상관하지 말구요
And it doesn't matter how I got it.
오, 어떻게 얻었는지
잘 알겠는 걸
Oh, I got a pretty good idea how you got it.
딜로렌티스 부인이
제이슨에게 메일을 보낸 게 아니라면
If Mrs. DiLaurentis didn't
send that email to Jason,
누구를 위해 보낸 거지?
then who was it for?
All we know for sure is it wasn't Jason.
우리가 분명히 아는 건
제이슨은 아니었다는 거지
그의 엄마가 죽던 밤에
그는 알콜중독 치료 모임에서
He was at that dry-out place
with no less than half a dozen people
자그마치 6명의 사람들과
함께 있었고
the night his mom died,
and we were in New York.
우리는 뉴욕에 있었지
So he's in the clear.
그럼 그는 결백하다는 거군
실망한 거 같아 보이는데
You sound disappointed.
No.
아냐
약간은.
우리가 했던 일을 생각했었어
A little.
I just thought that we had something.
♪ Babes, with four inch heels,
airbrushed nails ♪
♪ At the club, a killer babe ♪
♪ Babes ♪
♪ Back and forth, on the stage ♪
♪ Couldn't keep my eyes
off that killer babe ♪
♪ Girls, girls, girls ♪
♪ Women, women are babes, killer babes ♪
커밍 아웃할 때 기분이 어땠어?
What was it like to come out?
그 얘기가 왜 나오는데?
Where is this coming from?
네게 진심으로
물어본 적이 없었을 뿐이야
I just never really asked you.
내 말은, 한 가지를 그만 두고
I mean,
what was it like to stop being one thing
또 다른 무언가가 되는
기분이 어때?
and then just become something else?
난 다른 것이 된 적이 없어
I wasn't becoming something else.
진정한 자신이 된 거지
I was becoming who I really am.
항상 알고 있었어?
You always knew?
인정할 수 없었지
I couldn't admit it.
But you knew?
하지만 알고 있었구나?
Yeah.
그래
난 아니야
Not me.
내가 대체 무엇인지
결코 알지 못했어
I never knew who the hell I was.
시간 기록에 의하면
That time stamp means that your mother wrote
경찰서에서 아줌마가 목격되고
that 2 hours after the last time
두 시간 후에
아줌마는 이걸 쓰신 거예요
anybody saw her at that police station.
그리고 아줌마는
쓰는 걸 끝마치지도 못했어요
And she never finished writing it.
아줌마는 그걸 보내려던 사람의
She didn't even enter an address
주소에 조차
들어가지 못 했어요
to whom she meant to send.
엄마가 마음을 바꿨겠지
Maybe she changed her mind.
무엇이 그렇게 했을까요?
What would make her do that?
너라면 무엇이
네 마음을 바꾸게 하겠니?
What would make you change your mind?
그러한 메시지라면...
A message like that...
is something that I would
want to deliver personally.
저라면 직접
전해주고 싶었을 거예요
So she got up from her computer,
그래서 아줌마는
컴퓨터에서 일어났고
she walked out the front door
현관문으로 걸어 나가서
누군가에게 알리가 살아 있다고
말해주러 갔고
and she went to go tell somebody
that Ali was alive and that things
사람들이 알리가 살아 있다는
사실을 알기 전에
were falling apart faster
than anybody could fix them.
그 사건이 벌어져 버린 거죠
Too bad she never got to give the message.
안타깝게도, 엄마는
이 메시지를 전해 주지 못하셨군
What if she did?
전해 주셨다면요?
아마도 그 사람,
아줌마가 메일을 썼던 그 사람,
Maybe that person,
the person she was writing to,
아줌마가 더 이상
보호해 줄 수 없다던 그 사람,
the one that she couldn't protect anymore,
그 사람이 아줌마를
죽였을 거예요
maybe that's who killed her.
Any idea who that could be?
그랬을 거라 생각이 드는
사람이 있니?
네, 엄청 많죠
Yeah, tons of ideas.
그들 모두는
무척 끔찍한 사람들이예요
All of them pretty nasty.
많이 들어봤을 법한
부질없는 이야기가 있지
There's a creaky saying you
hear a lot at the meetings:
올바르게 되고 싶니,
아니면 행복하고 싶니?
Do you want to be right or
do you want to be happy?
선택을 못하겠어요
I don't have that choice.
절대 못하죠
I never did.
손을 떼라, 스펜서
Cut your losses, Spencer.
가능할 때 그만 두라구
Get out while you still can.
이것만 기억해
그를 믿어선 안 돼
Then remember, you can't trust him.
누구를 믿어선 안 되죠?
I can't trust who?
Our father.
너와 나의 아버지 말이야
당신이 그 옥상에
있었기에 다행이예요
I'm glad you were on that roof.
당신이 우리를 살렸어요
고마워요
You saved us. Thank you.
You're welcome.
천만에
We were scared that you were gonna die,
Ezra.
우린 당신이 죽을까봐
두려웠어요, 에즈라
So was I.
나도 마찬가지야
I'm glad you didn't.
당신이 죽지 않아 다행이예요
여기엔 왜 온거니, 앨리슨
그것 때문에?
Why are you here, Alison, with that?
Aria let me read it.
아리아가 읽어보게 해 줬어요
나는 뭔가를 찾고 있었어요
I was looking for something.
Did you find it?
찾았니?
전혀 못 찾았어요
Not all of it.
알 필요가 있는 것이 아니었어요
내가 살아있다면 말이죠
Not what I need to know
if I'm gonna stay alive.
더 있지 않나요?
There's more, isn't there?
당신은 모든 걸 보고
모든 걸 들었어요
All the watching,
all the listening that you did.
You didn't destroy all of it.
You couldn't have.
그것들 모두를 없애지 않았어요
당신은 그럴 수 없었을 거예요
If there was anything left,
만약 남아있는 게 있다면
아리아를 도울 수
있을지도 몰라서
the only thing preventing me from burning it
태워버리지 않은 것 뿐이야
is the possibility that it would help Aria,
if she would let me help.
아리아가 내 도움을
바란다면 말이지만
Well,
then you better keep it in a safe place.
뭐, 그렇다면, 당신은 그걸
안전한 곳에 보관해야 할 거예요
Did Aria know you were coming here?
네가 여기 온 걸
아리아가 알고 있니?
아뇨
No.
아리아에게 말해
Tell her.
완전 솔직하게요?
Absolute honesty?
That's all I got left.
그게 나에게 남은 모든 것이야
그러길 바래요
I hope it's enough.
뭐 좀 먹을래?
Do you want anything to eat?
아니, 커피면 돼
No, just coffee.
이 늦은 시간에
커피를 원한다구?
You're gonna have a coffee this late?
Seven-tenths of my body
is made up of caffeine.
내 몸의 70프로는
카페인으로 이루어져 있어
I have to maintain a consistent level.
항상 그 수준을
유지해야 한다구
Order for me?
내 거 주문해 줄래?
여기 있었네, 감성적인 소녀
Hi there, girly-girl.
네게 물어볼 것이 있어
I need to ask you a question.
Shoot.
쏴봐
Metaphorically speaking.
비유적으로 말해본 거야
When you and I were going through
너와 내가 극기 훈련소
실습을 할 때
glamour boot camp together,
you knew Ali was alive.
넌 알리가 살아 있다는 걸
알고 있었어
Is that what she told you?
걔가 말해준 거니?
Well, it's the truth, isn't it?
어쨌든, 그건 사실이야, 안 그래?
요점은 알리는 떠났었다는 거야
The point is she was gone.
That could either create a hole
or an opportunity for you and me
그건 상실감으로
가슴에 구멍을 내던지
너와 내가 서로 도와서
피라미드를 만들어 내던지 둘 중 하나였지
to help each other up the pyramid.
You didn't help me, you changed me.
넌 나를 도왔던 게 아니라,
넌 날 변하게 했어
넌 내 머리를 염색시키고,
알리의 옷을 입게 하고,
You made me dye my hair,
you made me wear her clothes,
알리처럼 걷고,
말하게 만들었어
you made me walk like her, talk like her.
그리고 네가 그렇게 되도록
내가 정말 얼마나 노력을 했니?
And exactly how much pushback
did I get from you on that?
알리는 떠나 버렸지만
넌 걔가 돌아오길 바랬던 거야
Ali was gone, but you wanted her back.
Why?
왜 그랬던 거지?
Reality check?
You didn't like being Hefty Hanna
현실을 직시할래?
넌 무거운 한나 같지 않고
난 더이상 루저 모나 같지 않아
anymore than I liked being Loser Mona.
How about a little gratitude?
감사 인사 정도는
해야 하는 것 아냐?
뭘 감사해야 하는데?
Gratitude for what?
If I hadn't given you the Ali upgrade,
내가 널 알리로
업그레이드 해 주지 않았다면
where would you be?
네가 어디 있을 거라 생각하니?
I'd still be me.
난 여전히 여기 있을 거야
그러면 누가
무거운 한나를 기억할까?
And who remembers her?
너 조차도 기억 못 하잖아
Not even you.
에밀리가 차에서
문자를 보냈는데
And then Emily texts from the car that Jason
뉴욕과 로즈우드에서 일이 벌어질 때
제이슨 오빠는 알리바이가 있어
has an alibi for what happened
in New York and Rosewood.
Wait. Jason actually told you
잠깐. 제이슨이 정말로
네 아빠를 믿지 말라고 했어?
that you shouldn't trust your own father?
그 이상이였어
More than that.
마치 D부인이 우리 아빠에게
더 이상 당신을 보호할 수 없어요
He made it seem like Mrs. D was writing
to my dad, "I can't protect you anymore."
라고 쓴 것처럼
보이게 하더라구
That's crazy.
미친 소리야
그래, 너도 알다시피, 미쳤지
Well, crazy, as you know,
여기에서 일어나는 일들은
상황에 따라 달라진다구
around here works on a sliding scale.
알리의 무덤에 있던
그 소녀를
I mean, look, I know that I didn't kill
that girl in Ali's grave, I know that.
난 죽이지 않았잖아
난 그걸 안다구
But I can't prove it and I really think
하지만 난 그걸
증명할 수 없고
내 부모님은 나를
믿지 않는 것 같아
that my parents don't believe me.
부모님들이 그 일에 대해
아무 말도 안하시려는 거니?
They wouldn't do anything about that,
would they?
매우 흥미로운 질문이지만
That's a very interesting question,
그래서 네게
돌아와야만 했던 거야
and I will have to get back to you on it.
에즈라 선생님에게
가 보라고 한 거 미안해
I'm so sorry you had to go talk to Ezra.
Yeah, well, we had to know
그래, 어쨌든, 우린
그가 뉴욕에서의 일에 대해
어떻게 말할 생각이었는지
알아야 했으니까
what he was going to say about New York.
누군가가 가서
해야할 필요가 있었어
But somebody else could
have gone and done that.
No, not really.
꼭 그렇진 않았지만
너 괜찮니?
Are you okay?
뭐 필요한 거 있어?
Do you need anything?
그래, 그 일이
일어나지 않았다고 믿고 싶어
Yeah, I need to know that it didn't happen.
극장에서의 샤나의 일 말이야
Shana in the theater.
하지만 일어난 일이지
But it did.
앨리슨?
Alison?
Hey, I thought that was you. Wasn't sure.
너라고 생각은 했다
확신은 없없지만 말이다
안녕하세요, 헤이스팅스 씨
Hello, Mr. Hastings.
How are you doing? You holding up?
어떻게 지내니?
잘 견디고 있는 거니?
I'm fine.
잘 지내요
감사합니다
Thanks.
잘 됐구나
That's good.
너 혼자서
밖에 있는 걸 보니
I'm a little surprised to see you out here
all by yourself.
조금 놀랐다
I can't hide in my room forever.
영원히 내 방에
숨어 지낼 순 없잖아요
외출하는 것이
아직 무섭더라도
Even if I'm still scared I have to get out
or else I never will.
결코 그러진 않을 거예요
Yeah, but you have police at the house,
right?
그래, 하지만 집엔
경찰을 불렀겠지?
I do.
그랬죠
But I know my way around this town
하지만 어떤 경찰 보다도
better than any cop.
이 지역 지리를 알아요
I can get out if I want to.
내가 원할 땐
외출을 할 수 있죠
Yeah, maybe, but under the circumstances,
그래, 그렇겠지
하지만 지금 상황에선
I think it'd be a good idea
if I gave you a ride home.
내가 너를 집까지
바래다 주는 게 좋겠구나
너 여기 나와 있는 거
우리 엄마가 아시니?
Does my mom know you're out here?
너희 엄마는
안에서 기다려도 된다고 하셨어
She said I could wait inside.
I told her I was okay here.
여기가 더 낫다고 말씀드렸지
Your mom knows we're fighting.
우리가 싸우고 있는 걸
네 엄마는 알고 계시더라
We're not fighting.
우린 싸우고 있는 게 아니야
싸웠었던 거지
We're done fighting.
Which makes us what?
그게 우리에게 어떤 차이지?
We go to the same school,
we used to be teammates,
우린 같은 학교를 다니고
같은 팀에 있었어
maybe we'll be friends.
우린 친구가 될 수 있을 거야
I practiced what I'm gonna say to you.
네게 할 말을 연습했었어
그거 아니?
Did you know that?
I talked to myself the whole way over here.
나는 여기서
혼자말을 반복했었어
I'm pretty convincing.
꽤 설득력이 있었지
Then I get to this porch
and I forget everything.
그런데 현관에서 일어나니까
다 까먹어 버렸어
All I can say is, "I love you."
내가 할 수 있는 말은
너를 사랑한다는 게 전부야
Like if I say it just right,
it'll fix things.
내가 제대로 말한 거라면
다시 시작할 수 있겠지
Somehow you'll hear it differently this time
이번엔 좀
다르게 들렸을 거고
and everything will be all right.
모든 일은
다 잘 될 거야.
I'm sorry.
미안해
매우 좋지 않게 들리는구나
That doesn't sound very good.
가는 게 낫겠어
I better go.
페이지
Paige...
넌 가장 좋은 사람을
만날 자격이 있어
You deserve the best of everything.
That's what I had.
난 만났었지
이 시간에
어디 있는 거죠, 젊은 양반?
Where have you been at this hour, young man?
좋아, 끝까지 들어봐
Okay, hear me out.
네 엄마에게 말하지 않는다면
Pretzels that I will share with you
이 프레첼을
너와 나눠 먹지
if you don't tell your mother.
Deal.
좋아요
You know the world's in a sorry state
내가 짠 음식을
몰래 먹어야 하는 게
when I have to make a
secret out of eating salt.
세상에서 가장
곤란한 일이라는 걸 알잖니
Mrs. DiLaurentis wrote this
the night that she died
딜로렌티스 부인이 죽던 밤에
경찰서에서 돌아온 후
부인이 이걸 썼어요
after she got back from the police station.
보내진 못했죠
She never sent it.
내 생각에 부인은 이걸
직접 전해주길 원했고
I think she wanted to deliver it in person
and that's why she's dead.
그게 부인이 죽은 이유죠
Is this a magic trick?
마술 트릭인가요?
Are you going to make it disappear?
사라지게 하시려는 거예요?
This doesn't mean anything.
이건 아무런 의미도 없는 거다
모든 것에는
의미가 있어요, 아빠
Every thing means something, Dad.
Who was she trying to protect
부인이 보호하려던 사람이 누구이고
and why did she suddenly
feel like she had to stop?
왜 부인은 갑자기
중단해야 한다고 느꼈을까요?
Was it because Alison was alive?
앨리슨이 살아있었기 때문인가요?
부인은 누구에게
이걸 쓴 걸까요?
Who was she writing this to?
아빠를 가만 둬
Leave him alone.
우린 대화 중이었다구
We're having a conversation.
니가 생각하는 대화가 뭔지 알지
I know what your idea of a conversation is.
그건 신경쓰지 말아라
Don't worry about that.
Oh, that's a grand gesture,
오, 대단한 행동이었지만
디지털 세대에선
쓸모없는 행동이라구
but it doesn't amount to
anything in a digital age.
이 여자는 미쳤었어
This woman was crazy.
부인은 미쳤지만 두려웠던 거야
She was crazy and afraid.
그만해! 둘 다
Enough! Both of you.
사람이 죽었는데, 너희 둘은
People are dead, you two are acting like
바닷가에서 돌아오는
5살짜리 어린아이처럼 짜증을 부리는구나
cranky little 5-year-olds on
the way back from the beach.
더 이상 같은 편끼리
싸우지 말아라
No more friendly fire.
확실히 알아 들었니?
Have I made myself clear?
Dad, maybe we should tell her.
아빠, 우린 얘한테
말해줘야 할까봐요
No. Don't.
아니. 그러지 말아라
Spencer, go upstairs.
스펜서, 올라가라
What?
뭐라구요?
Go upstairs.
올라가라구
농담하시는군요
You've got to be kidding me.
내가 농담하는 것 같아 보이니?
Do I look like I'm kidding?
그게 좋은 생각인 거 같다, 스펜서
Maybe that's a good idea, Spencer.
무슨 일이죠?
What is going on?
It's complicated.
복잡한 일이야
아니, 사실, 단순한 문제야
No, actually, it's simple.
You can't lie about something
you don't know anything about.
네가 알지 못하는 일에 대해서
거짓말만 하지 않으면 돼
앨리슨이 들를지도 모른다고
경고했어야 했어요
I meant to warn you that
Alison might stop by.
I just didn't think that she'd move so fast.
걔가 그렇게 빨리
움직일 거라곤 생각 못했어요
노크하는 소리를 듣고는
I just heard a knock on the door
너일 거라고 생각했었어
and I thought it might be you.
왜인지는 모르겠어
I don't know why.
난 솔직히 다시는
너를 볼 수 없을 거라고 생각했어
I honestly thought I
would never see you again.
그래요, 저도 같은 생각을 했었어요
Yeah, I was kind of thinking the same thing.
하지만 내가 다시 여기에 온 건
범죄현장으로 돌아온 거예요
But here I am once again,
back at the scene of the crime.
여기서는 범죄는 없었는데
There's no crime here.
내가 알고 있는
방식이 아닌데
Not the way I see it.
Look, Ezra, I didn't just come over here
에즈라, 난 앨리슨에 대한
경고를 해 주기 위해
to warn you about Alison.
여기에 온 게 아니예요
지난 번에 당신에게
말해야 했던 걸
I came here to tell you something
말해주기 위해 온 거예요
that I should have told you before.
아리아, 내게 어떤 것도
말해줄 필요는 없어
Aria, you don't need to tell me anything.
No, listen.
아니요, 들으세요
더 이상 샤나에 대한
걱정을 할 필요 없어요
You don't have to worry about Shana anymore.
She's dead.
샤나는 죽었어요
And I know that she's dead,
because I'm responsible.
그리고 그애의 죽음은
내 책임이기 때문이예요
책임이라니 무...무슨 말이야?
Wh-What do you mean "responsible"?
I mean that I killed her...
내가 죽였다는 말이예요...
뉴욕에 있을 때,
병원을 나선 후에요
in New York after I left the hospital.
I just meant to stop her.
I never meant to kill her.
난 샤나를 멈추려고 했어요
결코 죽이려는 게 아니었다구요
어쨌든, 그게 내 자신에게
지금까지 해온 말이예요
Anyway,
that's what I've been telling myself.
하지만 순간적으로
일어난 일이었고
But it was just in that moment,
난 몰랐다구요
I don't know.
내가 어떻게 도와줄까?
How can I help?
Same shade of blonde this time?
이번에도 똑같이 금발로 할까요?
아뇨, 이번엔 달라요
No, not the same.
변해야 할 때에요
It's time for a change.
♪ Everything that you promise now ♪
♪ It's all a lie ♪
♪ All the pleasure
that you purchase now ♪
♪ It's all a lie ♪
♪ Every story that I'm hearin' now ♪
♪ A lie ♪
♪ And everything about her style ♪
♪ It's all a lie ♪
♪ Lie, lie, lie ♪
♪ (song continues indistinct) ♪
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com